# **DEVONNA (TRACY) DEPP**

# Software Developer



#### PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Prior to beginning my journey in software development, I worked as a freelance creative and professional services consultant. During this time, I developed a love for web content and managing websites using content management systems. After 10 years of developing and maintaining websites using content management systems, I decided I wanted to know the "how and why" behind websites and applications. I am excited to begin my new journey as a software developer.

#### **TECHINCAL SKILLS**

- Python
   Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, Outlook, Access)
- Django
   Adobe Creative Suite
- React
   CRM (Raiser's Edge, Salesforce, Nationbuilder, EveryAction)
- HTML/CSS
   Email Marketing Software (EMMA, Constant Contact, Mail Chimp)
- JavaScript
   CMS (Wordpress, Wix, Squarespace, Big Commerce, Shopify)

### **TECHINCAL EDUCATION**

January 2021 - June 2021

#### Nashville Software School - Software Developer

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects using the agile and scrum implementation.

Buitd single page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.

Create CRUD applications during individual and group projects

Utilize 3rd party APIs to include data in applications

Source code version control using Git/Github

Project management with Github Projects

#### **PROJECTS**

#### dude, where's my stuff? | Personal Project | View Code

Web application built in React used to record personal items that friends have borrowed and not returned. The goal of this app was to create a useful, simple, browser-based single page application. Dude, where's my stuff is built using:

- · React for an interactive UI
- · Javascript to write component logic to manage their own state
- · Styled using CSS Frameworks (customized design)
- Persistent local data storage using json-server

#### **Nutshell | Group Project | View Code**

- Worked on a team of four people to create a single-page social network dashboard that allows users to save tasks, articles, events and connect with friends.
- Responsible for the CRUD functionality of the tasks pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### d. tracy depp consulting, Remote - Professional & Creative Services Consultant

November 2016 - Present

- Manages multiple websites using Wordpress, SquareSpace, Wix and NationBuilder
- Redesign and update websites
- Develops email marketing communications using NationBuilder, EMMA, Mailchimp and Constant Contact
- Maintains membership databases using Salesforce and Nationbuilder
- · Performs various administrative tasks, as needed

# **DEVONNA (TRACY) DEPP**

# Software Developer



## AssuredLink, Bowling Green, KY — Business Operations Manager

November 2016 - April 2018

- Worked with the management team to craft strategic vision, then aligned organizational resources with it
- Set an effective agenda and ensured performance goals were met
- Managed administrative procedures and processes to maintain fiscal accountability and control, equitable and fair personnel practices, and
  efficiency of operations
- Oversaw and coordinated fundraising and donor management activities
- Developed other revenue sources including business arrangements and funding proposals
- Developed and maintained effective working relationships with members of management team
- Served as a mentor, guide and coach to staff
- · Created and managed the annual budget
- Ensured compliance with all appropriate regulations
- Ensured appropriate information flow both within and outside the organization
- Represented the organization, serves as its public face as appropriate
- · Oversaw marketing, media relations, and public relations

## Tennessee Nurses Association, Nashville, TN — Marketing Communications Consultant

- Increased membership by 13% over 3 years.
- Directed the processing of membership accounts for 2600+ members across the state of Tennessee
- Increased social media presence and press coverage
- Designed and managed internal and external email marketing and communications using Constant Contant and InDesign.
- Managed website using Raiser's Edge and Wordpress.
- Maintained Raiser's Edge donor database with 4000+ constituents with 100% accuracy

### W.O.M.E.N., Nashville, TN — Executive/Communications Assistant

May 2011 - May 2013

May 2016 - December 2019

- Assistant to the CEO and performed various administrative tasks.
- Developed and implemented a public relations strategy resulting in increased press coverage and awards
- Sourced and secured funding by writing grant proposals (\$20,000 raised)
- Developed and implemented a strategic social media strategy
- Designed and managed Wordpress website
- Assisted in program development and coordination of special events and meetings
- Developed and distributed content for fundraising, marketing and public relation materials (print & electronic)
- Orientated, trained and supervised volunteers and interns
- Maintained Access database of 250 clients and stakeholders

#### Deloitte Services, LP, Nashville, TN — Wireless Compliance Lead

2007-2010

- Acted as a liaison between all Deloitte employees and the wireless carriers
- · Developed and implemented internal audit processes to streamline server and device compliance
- Managed procurement and billing for over 6000 corporate wireless accounts
- Maintained detailed database of compliance issues using Microsoft Access
- · Handled all inquiries for partners, principals and directors
- Developed training materials
- Trained and monitored a team in India on all processes

#### **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School Full Stack Web Development Certificate Argosy Univeristy
MSM, Business Management

University of Tennessee - Knoxville BS, Busines Administration, Marketing, Speech Communications & Advertising